Rohan Alexander

rohan.alexander@utoronto.ca rohanalexander.com

SUMMARY

I trained as an economist and then worked at Australia's central bank and a private economic consultancy. As part of a small team I then co-founded a start-up that was bought. I am a post-doc at the Faculty of Information at the University of Toronto where I apply machine learning methods to questions in social sciences. I am an Australian citizen who lives in Toronto, Canada, and holds an open Canadian work permit.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-founder and Director, GoCampaign

July 2011 to May 2015

- As a co-founder and director of GoCampaign (later GoCatalyze), a data analysis tool, I
 was responsible for the creation and development of a business along with Andrew
 Barnes, Chris Eigeland and Chris Hood.
- In addition to helping create and run the business I had many specific responsibilities including creating marketing material and websites; making pitch decks; customer onboarding and service; presenting; market testing; and some minor managerial duties.
- GoCatalyze completed the ANZ Innovyz START accelerator program in 2013 and won the iAward Data Category in 2014. GoCatalyze is now part of GO1, which is a learning management system provider.

Economist, The Centre for International Economics

January 2012 to August 2013

- The CIE is a privately-owned economic consultancy.
- I contributed to reports for public- and private-sector clients as part of a small team.
- Topics included: housing sector taxation; the global meat market; wheat price elasticities; variations to modern awards; migration; and labor markets.

Cadet/Analyst/Senior Analyst, Reserve Bank of Australia

February 2009 to December 2011

- I researched topics related to banknotes, for example an econometric analysis of banknote demand during the 2007-08 financial crisis.
- I was also responsible for maintaining and analyzing counterfeit banknote datasets, and gave banknote-related presentations to the public.

CONSULTING EXPERIENCE

Researcher, World Health Organization March 2019 to present

- I work on a casual basis to complete a specific project relating to maternal cause of death estimation.
- This involves text cleaning and analysis using R.

Consultant, Grosvenor Public Sector Advisory

April 2017 to February 2019

- I worked on a casual basis to complete a specific project for the European Commission relating to public procurement data.
- This involved me: identifying data sources; preparing for and supporting data acquisition; conducting data quality confirmation; helping with survey design and validation; and some minor managerial responsibilities.
- Despite the fact that our team was spread across three cities, the client was remote, and at times the dataset was not in English, the client twice re-engaged us.

Economist, The Centre for International Economics

August 2015 to November 2015

• I consulted at the CIE on a casual basis to complete a specific project for a client relating to valuing public sector outputs.

ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Toronto July 2019 to present

EDUCATION

Ph. D (Econ), Australian National University

February 2015 to present

My research applies quantitative methods to questions in Australian political and economic history. For instance, in one paper I digitize and analyze the words spoken in the Australian federal parliament using a Bayesian hierarchical model in R; in another I analyze spatial voting using Stata and R; and in a third I exploit differences-in-differences between labor market outcomes for brothers using Python, R and Stata.

M. Econ, Australian National University

February 2012 to November 2012

B. Econ, University of Queensland

February 2004 to November 2008

TEACHING

Australian National University

I tutored (equivalent to 'teaching assistant'): Macroeconomics 3; Microeconomics 3; Behavioural Economics; Business Economics; Microeconomics 1; and Foundations of Economic and Financial Models.

University of Queensland

I tutored: Microeconomic Policy; Microeconomic Theory; and Introductory Microeconomics.

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-reviewed journal articles

Rohan Alexander and Zach Ward, 2018, 'Age At Arrival and Assimilation In The Age Of Mass Migration', *The Journal of Economic History*, 78(3), 904-937.

Other papers including academic working papers, published opinion articles, and blog posts are available on my website.

SIDE PROJECT

Petit Poll

April 2016 to present

Petit Poll combines non-representative surveys that we gather ourselves with a Bayesian MRP model to produce Australian political polling. I am responsible for all aspects of our surveys, marketing and communication, and have shared responsibility for our model.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient in R; familiar with: Python, Stata, SQL, and HTML/CSS.

Proficient in Word, Excel and PowerPoint, and their Apple and Google equivalents.

CITIZENSHIP AND WORK PERMIT

Australian citizen with an open Canadian work permit that expires on July 2023.

REFERENCES

John Tang	Stefan Gassner	Chris Eigeland
Senior Lecturer	Associate Director	COO
Australian National University	Grosvenor	GO1
john.tang@anu.edu.au	stefangassner@grosvenor.com.au	chris@go1.com